What actually happens when I tap a
credit card? The tech inside your credit
card is incredible. Imagine you shrink
down to the size of your card. Here's
the chip. Not that, it's actually hidden
underneath the contact pad. And the
moment that you tap it, you're setting
off an incredible chain reaction around
the world. In those few seconds before
the machine accepts your card, the chip
sends a radio signal to the card reader
with your card data, encrypted with a
secret one-time code that makes your
information useless to anybody who would
try to steal it. It's similar with
mobile payments. When you [music] tap
your phone, the chip sends a stand-in
number, so your real 16-digit number is
never shared. That's why chips are more
secure than the old-school swipe. Then,
that information travels through a
payment network like MasterCard. That
acts like a switchboard, connecting
banks and merchants in over 200
countries and territories. They work
with banks to make sure that security is
in every layer of this network, with AI
and cybersecurity and privacy to protect
all of their users. That includes
determining if the payment looks like
you or looks like a scammer. Is this a
normal location for you? Is the amount
unusual?
Does this match any other suspicious
activity anywhere in the world? Do you
have enough credit for this purchase? If
everything looks okay, your bank sends
back an approval. And then kicks off a
behind-the-scenes process for the money
to move between banks. And all of that,
the encryption, the routing, the review,
the final yes or no, it usually happens
in less than a second. That invisible
tech layer is what makes it possible to
pay simply and securely almost anywhere
in the world with just one tap. So,
MasterCard isn't a credit card company.
It's a technology company sitting at the
intersection of security and innovation
and inclusion. And that's priceless. To
learn more, follow @Mastercard on
Instagram.